Guide to the Harold Dwight Lasswell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- General Files, 1920-1978; Series I; 44 linear feet (106 boxes, 2 folio boxes)
  - Case, Everett M.
    See: box 69, folders 899-901
  - Casey, Ralph D., 1941-1943, 1946-1948, 1952-1954 (Box 25, Folder 313)
  - Cassidy, Richard J., 1965-1973, undated (Box 25, Folder 314-315)
  - Catlin, Sir George, 1947-1957, 1964-1973 (Box 25, Folder 316-318)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1954-1973 (Box 25, Folder 319-320)
    See also: box 92, folder 1131 See also: box 218, folder 56
  - Center for World Order Studies
    See: box 99, folders 1204-1205
  - Chafee, Zechariah, Jr.
    See: box 26, folders 334-338
  - Chapin, John S., 1942-1943 (Box 25, Folder 321)
  - Chapman, John W., 1965-1966, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 322)
  - Chen, Lung-chu, 1965-1973, 1976, undated (Box 26, Folder 323-324)
  - Cherin, William B., 1936-1947 (Box 26, Folder 325-326)
    See also: box 184, folders 182-191
  - City University of New York, 1966-1973 (Box 26, Folder 327)
    See also: box 50, folders 694-695
  - Civilian Conservation Corps - Camp William James, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 328)
  - The Clark (Grenville) Fund at Dartmouth College, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box 26, Folder 329)
  - Clarke, James, 1946-1947, 1952-1953 (Box 26, Folder 330)
  - Cleveland, Harlan, 1964-1966, 1969, 1972-1974 (Box 26, Folder 331)
  - Columbia University, 1954, 1961-1974 (Box 26, Folder 332)
  - Columbia University Press, 1952, 1954, 1959-1961, 1965, 1967, 1970, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 333)
  - Commission on the Freedom of the Press, 1943-1944 March 28 (Box 26, Folder 334-338)
  - Commission on the Freedom of the Press, 1944 March 29-1948, undated (Box 27, Folder 339-351)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1943-1948, 1950-1954 1957, undated (Box 28, Folder 352-354)
    See also: box 34, folder 462
  - Committee on International Exchange of Persons, 1964-1965, 1970-1973 (Box 28, Folder 355)
  - Communication, 1970-1973 (Box 28, Folder 356)
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, 1943-1971, undated (Box 28, Folder 357-360)
    See also: box 46, folders 642-645 See also: box 34, folders 455-457 See also: box 34, folder 459 See also: box 49, folder 691
  - Coordinating Center for Democratic Opinion, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 361)
  - Cornell-Peru Project, 1959-1960 (Box 28, Folder 362-363)
    See also: box 30, folders 399-400 See also: box 31, folder 404 See also: box 43, folders 603-607 See also: box 52, folder 734 See also: box 59, folder 809
  - Corning Glass Conference, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 364)
  - Corris, Richard, 1967-1968, 1971-1976 (Box 28, Folder 365)
  - Cosmos Club, 1946-1948, 1953-1954, 1958-1975 (Box 28, Folder 366-367)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1946-1947, 1965, 1967, 1969-1977 (Box 28, Folder 368-369)
  - Council on Internal Communications, 1967-1968, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 370)
  - Cowan, Louis G., 1964-1969, 1973-1976 (Box 29, Folder 371)
  - D, 1938-1976, undated (Box 29, Folder 372-382)
  - David, Henry, 1952-1957, 1961-1974 (Box 29, Folder 383-384)
    See also: box 68, folders 893-895
  - Davidson, Frank P. and Roger, 1947-1948, 1956, 1964-1973 (Box 30, Folder 385-386)
    See also: box 47, folders 648-650
  - Davison, W. Phillips, 1947, 1957, 1965-1972 (Box 30, Folder 387)
    See also: box 78, folder 980
  - De Grazia, Alfred, 1949-1973 (Box 30, Folder 388-389)
  - De Grazia, Edward, 1952-1974 (Box 30, Folder 390)
  - De Grazia, Sebastian, 1942-1976 (Box 30, Folder 391-392)
  - Deutsch, Karl W., 1957, 1963-1976 (Box 30, Folder 393)
  - Dewitt, Paul
    See: box 13, folder 146
  - Dexter, Louis A., 1940, 1946-1956, 1965-1976 (Box 30, Folder 394-395)
  - Dictionary of the History of Ideas, 1967-1970 (Box 30, Folder 396)
  - Dillard, Hardy C., 1942, 1965-1976 (Box 30, Folder 397)
  - Dixon, John, 1942, 1964-1971, undated (Box 30, Folder 398)
  - Dobyns, Henry F., 1965-1973 (Box 30, Folder 399-400)
  - Dobyns, Henry F., 1962-1964 (Box 30, Folder 401-402)
  - Dobyns, Henry F., 1968, undated (Box 31, Folder 403)
    See also: box 31, folder 404 See also: box 43, folders 603-607 See also: box 28, folders 362-363 See also: box 86, folder 1063
  - Doughty, Paul L., 1965-1973 (Box 31, Folder 404)
    See also: box 30, folders 399-400 See also: box 43, folders 603-607 See also: box 28, folders 362-363
  - Dovring, Karin, 1951-1972, 1987, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 405-406)
  - Dror, Yehezkel, 1969-1974, undated (Box 31, Folder 407-408)
    See also: box 19, folders 241-245
  - DuBois, Cornelius
  - Dunn, Frederick S., 1947-1956 (Box 31, Folder 409)
  - E, 1943-1976 (Box 31, Folder 410-418)
  - East-West Center, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 419)
  - Easton, David, 1949-1967 (Box 31, Folder 420)
  - Edinger, Lewis J., 1965-1967, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 421)
  - Educational Television and Radio Center, 1952-1958 (Box 32, Folder 422-425)
  - Elliott, William Yandall, 1949-1959 (Box 32, Folder 426)
  - Elsten, Harold, 1951-1956 (Box 32, Folder 427)
  - Enciclopedia, Italiana, 1971-1977, undated (Box 32, Folder 428)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1946-1973 (Box 32, Folder 429-431)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica Films Inc., 1945-1960, undated (Box 32, Folder 432-435)
    See also: box 12, folders 133-138 See also: box 16, folders 195-205 See also: box 22, folder 270 See also: box 32, folders 432-435 See also: box 34, folder 462
  - Eulau, Heinz, 1941-1977 (Box 32, Folder 436)
    See also: box 177, folders 135-136
  - Evaluation of School Broadcasts, 1940-1941 (Box 33, Folder 437)
  - Evans, Luther H., 1941-1956 (Box 33, Folder 438)
  - F, 1941-1977, undated (Box 33, Folder 439-448)
  - Fairbank, John K., 1947, 1961, 1966, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 449)
  - Falk, Richard A., 1965-1976 (Box 33, Folder 450-451)
    See also: box 23, folders 485-486
  - Farrell, James T., 1950-1954, 1964-1969, undated (Box 34, Folder 452-454)
  - Feingold, Jessica, 1964-1970 (Box 34, Folder 455-457)
    See also: box 28, folders 357-360 See also: box 46, folders 642-645 See also: box 34, folder 459
  - Felknor, Bruce L.
    See: box 16, folders 195-205 See: box 32, folders 429-431
  - Fellers, Bonner T., 1948-1950 (Box 34, Folder 458)
  - Fesler, James
    See: box 104, folder 1269
  - Finkelstein, Louise, 1946, 1951-1974, undated (Box 34, Folder 459)
    See also: box 28, folders 357-360
  - Fishkin, James S., 1970-1973, undated (Box 34, Folder 460)
  - Fitch, John S., III, 1968-1970 (Box 34, Folder 461)
  - Fletcher, C. Scott, 1946-1954, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 462)
    See also: box 28, folders 352-354 See also: box 32, folders 432-435 See also: box 36, folder 484
  - Ford Foundation, 1951-1953 (Box 34, Folder 463)
  - Ford Foundation, 1954-1972 (Box 35, Folder 464-465)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1946-1951, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 466)
  - Fosdick, Raymond
  - Foundation for Integrative Education, Inc., 1967 (Box 35, Folder 467)
  - Fox, Merritt B., 1964-1974 (Box 35, Folder 468)
  - Fox, William T.R., 1944-1954, 1966-1973 (Box 35, Folder 469)
  - Franklin Publications, Inc. and Franklin Book Programs, Inc., 1952-1958, 1964, 1967-1977, undated (Box 35, Folder 470-476)
  - Free, Lloyd
  - Free Press, 1949-1975 (Box 35, Folder 477)
  - Freedman, Lawrence Z., 1953, 1964, 1970-1976 (Box 35, Folder 478)
  - Frenkel-Brunswick, Else, 1951-1957, undated (Box 35, Folder 479)
  - Frey, Frederick W., 1965-1973 (Box 36, Folder 480)
  - Fried, John H.E., 1946-1953, 1965-1971 (Box 36, Folder 481)
  - Friedman (originally Friedmann), Otto, 1948-1952, 1970-1975 (Box 36, Folder 482)
  - Friedrich, Carl J., 1946-1953, 1960-1973 (Box 36, Folder 483)
  - Fund for Adult Education, 1952-1957 (Box 36, Folder 484)
  - Fund for Education in World Order, 1967-1969 (Box 36, Folder 485-486)
    See also: box 49, folders 687-689
  - Fund for the Republic
    See: box 15, folders 179-188
  - Furniss, Edgar J., Jr.
  - G, 1939-1971 (Box 36, Folder 487-497)
  - G, 1972-1976, undated (Box 37, Folder 498-500)
  - Gardner, Richard N., 1951-1974 (Box 37, Folder 501-502)
  - Gaston, Jerry, 1965-1969 (Box 37, Folder 503)
  - Gans, John M., 1946-1952 (Box 37, Folder 504)
  - Geller, Alan, 1942 (Box 37, Folder 505)
  - George, Alexander L., 1941-1976 (Box 37, Folder 506-508)
  - George Washington University, 1953, 1964-1970 (Box 37, Folder 509)
  - Gerbner, George, 1964-1977, undated (Box 37, Folder 510)
    See also: box 96, folder 1172
  - Gilson, Mary B., 1947-1954, 1967-1969 (Box 37, Folder 511)
  - Glyphs
    See: box 65, folder 866
  - Godoy, Horacio N., 1965-1973 (Box 37, Folder 512-513)
  - Gogate, Rajoram V., 1950-1954 (Box 37, Folder 514)
  - Goldberg, Irwin, 1958-1964 (Box 37, Folder 515)
  - Goldsen, Joseph M., 1941-1952 (Box 38, Folder 516-526)
  - Goldsen, Joseph M., 1953-1976, undated (Box 39, Folder 527-536)
    See also: box 16, folders 195-205 See also: box 71, folders 915-920 See also: box 185, folders 192-210 See also: box 212, folders 1-5
  - Goldstein, Abraham
    See: box 105, folders 1279-1281
  - Goldstein, Joseph, 1967-1974 (Box 39, Folder 537)
    See also: box 38, folders 516-526
  - Gombrich, E.H., 1950-1953, 1965-1969 (Box 39, Folder 538)
  - Gorcin, Vasile, 1951, undated (Box 39, Folder 539)
  - Gorer, Geoffrey, 1942-1953, 1969, undated (Box 39, Folder 540)
  - Gorove, Stephen M., 1952-1972 (Box 39, Folder 541)
  - Gould, Wesley L., 1958, 1965-1975 (Box 39, Folder 542-543)
  - Greenfield, Edward L., 1961-1965 (Box 39, Folder 544)
  - Greenfield, Edward L., 1966-1970, undated (Box 40, Folder 545-548)
  - Greenfield, Michael
    See: box 39, folder 544
  - Greenstein, Fred I., 1959-1976 (Box 40, Folder 549-553)
  - Grierson, John
  - Grass, Bertram M., 1952, 1968-1970 (Box 40, Folder 554)
  - Grunwald, Edgar A., 1950, 1965-1972 (Box 40, Folder 555)
  - H, 1938-1951 (Box 40, Folder 556-561)
  - H, 1952-1972 (Box 41, Folder 562-576)
  - H, 1973-1977, undated (Box 42, Folder 577-578)
  - Haas, Ernest B., 1959-1970, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 579)
  - Hall, H. Duncan, 1946-1953 (Box 42, Folder 580)
  - Halpern, Abraham M., 1946-1947, 1961-1964, undated (Box 42, Folder 581-584)
  - Halpern, Benjamin, 1952, 1964-1965 (Box 42, Folder 585)
  - Hargrove, Erwin C., 1966-1969 (Box 42, Folder 586)
  - Hargrove, John Lawrence, 1971-1973 (Box 42, Folder 587)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1953-1962 (Box 42, Folder 588)
  - Harper and Row, 1964-1974 (Box 42, Folder 588)
  - Harvard University, 1946-1953, 1969-1973 (Box 42, Folder 589)
  - Haskins, Caryl P., 1946-1974 (Box 42, Folder 590)
  - Hawes, Marion
    See: box 5, folders 62-63
  - Hawley, Claude E., 1946-1972, undated (Box 42, Folder 591-592)
  - Headley, Anne Renouf
    See: box 25, folders 310-312
  - Heller, John H.
    See: box 70, folder 910
  - Helmer, Olaf
    See: box 47, folders 648-650
  - Helmick, Milton J., 1939-1952, undated (Box 43, Folder 593)
  - Hermann, Charles F.
    See: box 48, folders 663-664
  - Herzog, Elizabeth, 1941-1946, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 594)
  - Herzog, George, 1942-1970 (Box 43, Folder 595-598)
    See also: box 25, folder 305 See also: box 186, folders 211-233
  - Higgins, Rosalyn, 1967-1973 (Box 43, Folder 599)
  - Hoagland, Hudson, 1959-1968 (Box 43, Folder 600)
  - Hocking, William E.
  - Hoffman, Hester, 1957-1961 (Box 43, Folder 601)
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 1941-1951 (Box 43, Folder 602)
  - Holmberg, Allan R. and Laura, 1954-1972, undated (Box 43, Folder 603-607)
    See also: box 30, folders 399-400 See also: box 31, folder 404 See also: box 28, folders 362-363
  - Holmes (Oliver Wendell) Association, 1966-1971, undated (Box 43, Folder 608)
  - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, 1962-1972 (Box 43, Folder 609)
    See also: box 12, folders 139-141
  - Hopkins, Benjamin T., II, 1965-1975 (Box 44, Folder 610)
  - Hopkins, Raymond F., 1965-1973 (Box 44, Folder 611)
  - Horwitz, Robert, 1959-1978 (Box 44, Folder 612)
  - Howe, John, 1943-1966 (Box 44, Folder 613-614)
    See also: box 26, folders 334-338
  - Hudson, Robert M.
  - Hudson, Michael C., 1960-1961, 1969-1971 (Box 44, Folder 615)
  - Hughes, Thomas L., 1968-1971 (Box 44, Folder 616)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1956-1971 (Box 44, Folder 617)
  - Humphrey, Robert L., 1959-1975 (Box 44, Folder 618-619)
  - Humphrey, Robert L., 1966 (Box 44, Folder 620)
  - Humphrey, Robert L., 1974 (Box 45, Folder 621-624)
  - Huntington, Samuel P., 1959-1962, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 625)
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 1938-1969 (Box 45, Folder 626)
    See also: box 26, folders 334-338 See also: box 16, folders 195-205
  - Hynning, Clifford J., 1953-1954, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 627)
  - I, 1940-1977, undated (Box 46, Folder 628-637)
  - Admiration of Youth, Musée D'Orsay, 1953-1971 (Box 46, Folder 638)
  - Innes, John W., 1941-1957 (Box 46, Folder 639)
  - Institute for Educational Development, 1966-1971 (Box 46, Folder 640)
  - Institute for International Order, 1959-1961 (Box 46, Folder 641)
  - Institute for Policy Development
    See: box 25, folders 314-315
  - Institute for Religious and Social Studies, 1946-1967 (Box 46, Folder 642-645)
  - Institute for Religious and Social Studies, 1968-1975, undated (Box 47, Folder 646-647)
    See also: box 22, folders 266-269 See also: box 23, folder 279 See also: box 28, folders 357-360 See also: box 34, folders 455-457 See also: box 34, folder 459
  - Institute for Studies in Social Psychology and Public Opinion
    See: box 47, folder 658
  - Institute for the Future, 1966-1974, undated (Box 47, Folder 648-650)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs
    See: box 17, folder 345 See: box 81, folder 1019
  - Institute of Ethnic Affairs, Inc., 1946-1952 (Box 47, Folder 651)
  - Institute of Man and Science, 1967-1972 (Box 47, Folder 652)
  - Institute of Social and Behavioral Pathology, 1973, undated (Box 47, Folder 653)
  - International Association for Mass Communication Research, 1957-1973 (Box 47, Folder 654)
  - International Broadcast Institute, 1967-1976 (Box 47, Folder 655-656)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1961-1968 (Box 47, Folder 657)
  - International Journal of Opinion and Attitude Research, 1946-1950 (Box 47, Folder 658)
  - International Peace Academy, 1968-1971 (Box 47, Folder 659-662)
  - International Studies Association, 1968-1976, undated (Box 48, Folder 663-664)
  - International Study Center
    See: box 89, folder 1103
  - Investors Syndicate, 1947-1951 (Box 48, Folder 665-667)
  - Isard, Walter, 1962-1970, undated (Box 48, Folder 668-669)
    See also: box 101, folders 1228-1231
  - J, 1940-1978 (Box 48, Folder 670-676)
  - Jackson, Don D., 1955-1963 (Box 48, Folder 677)
  - Jacob, Philip E. and Betty, 1965-1968 (Box 48, Folder 678)
  - Jahoda, Marie, 1951-1956 (Box 48, Folder 679)
    See also: box 18, folder 231
  - Janis, Irving L., 1941-1942 (Box 48, Folder 680)
  - Janis, Irving L., 1943-1969 (Box 49, Folder 681-683)
  - Janowitz, Morris, 1946-1976 (Box 49, Folder 684-686)
    See also: box 87, folders 1076-1078
  - Jefferies, Jack P., 1953-1976 (Box 49, Folder 687-689)
  - Jenkins, William S., 1954-1958 (Box 49, Folder 690)
  - Jessup, Philip C., 1946-1971 (Box 49, Folder 691)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary
    See also: box 34, folder 459
  - Jha, Shashishekar, 1967-1972 (Box 49, Folder 692-693)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice
    - General, 1969-1972 (Box 50, Folder 694-695)
    - Faculty Seminars, 1969-1971 (Box 50, Folder 696-697)
    - Legal Education and Services Project, 1969-1970, undated (Box 50, Folder 698-702)
  - Johns Hopkins University. School of Advanced International Studies
    See: box 87, folder 1074
  - Johnson, Malcolm, 1953-1955, undated (Box 50, Folder 703)
  - Jones, Dorothy B., 1945-1973, undated (Box 50, Folder 704-707)
  - Jones, Ernest M., 1960-1970 (Box 50, Folder 708-709)
    See also: box 46, folder 640
  - Jones, S. Shepherd, 1946-1947 (Box 51, Folder 710)
  - Jossey-Bass, Allen, 1963-1971 (Box 51, Folder 711)
  - Journal of Conflict Resolution, 1959-1964 (Box 51, Folder 712)
  - Journal of Politics, 1967-1970 (Box 51, Folder 713)
  - K, 1941-1977 (Box 51, Folder 714-722)
  - Kail, Floyd, 1969-1973 (Box 51, Folder 723)
  - Kallen, Horace M.
    See: box 70, folder 911
  - Kampelman, Max, 1951-1967 (Box 51, Folder 724)
  - Kane, R. Keith, 1941-1942 February (Box 51, Folder 725-726)
  - Kane, R. Keith, 1942 March-1974 (Box 52, Folder 727-729)
  - Kaplan, Abraham, 1942-1972, undated (Box 52, Folder 730-731)
  - Kaplan, Jeremiah
    See: box 35, folder 477
  - Katz, Jay, 1967-1977, undated (Box 52, Folder 732)
  - Katzenbach, Nicholas, 1959-1972 (Box 52, Folder 733)
  - Kaufman, Herbert
    See: box 30, folder 393 See: box 104, folder 1269
  - Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner & Co., Ltd.
    See: box 82, folder 1030
  - Kennedy, John L., 1954-1970 (Box 52, Folder 734)
  - Kernig, C.D., 1968-1969 (Box 52, Folder 735)
  - Kirkpatrick, Evron
    See: box 7, folders 78-84 See: box 44, folders 613-614 See: box 52, folder 736
  - Kirkpatrick, Jeane, 1959-1976 (Box 52, Folder 736)
    See also: box 61, folder 832
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1946-1955 (Box 52, Folder 737)
  - Knopf (Alfred A.) Inc., 1938-1967 (Box 52, Folder 738)
  - Kosok, Michael, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 739)
  - Krastin, Karl, 1951-1976 (Box 52, Folder 740)
  - Kris, Ernst, 1941-1952, undated (Box 52, Folder 741)
  - Krould, Harry J., 1941 January-August (Box 52, Folder 742-743)
  - Krould, Harry J., 1941 August-1954, undated (Box 53, Folder 744-748)
  - Kutner, Luis, 1938-1963 (Box 53, Folder 749-753)
  - Kutner, Luis, 1964-1977, undated (Box 54, Folder 754-758)
  - L, 1938-1961 (Box 54, Folder 759-764)
  - L, 1962-1973 (Box 55, Folder 765-772)
  - L, 1974-1977, undated (Box 56, Folder 773)
  - Lane, Robert E., 1954-1971 (Box 56, Folder 774)
  - Lasswell, Anna P. and Linden, 1920-1943, undated (Box 56, Folder 775-787)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul F., 1941-1955 (Box 57, Folder 788)
  - Leiserson, Avery, 1948-1976 (Box 57, Folder 789)
  - Leites, Nathan, 1939-1970 (Box 57, Folder 790-792)
  - Lepawsky, Albert, 1946-1953, 1960-1974 (Box 57, Folder 793)
  - Lerner, Daniel, 1942-1952 (Box 57, Folder 794)
  - Lerner, Daniel, 1953-1977, undated (Box 58, Folder 795-797)
  - Lewis, Doris (Mrs. Paul), 1941-1943, 1966-1968 (Box 58, Folder 798-800)
  - Lewis, Paul, 1940-1973 (Box 58, Folder 801-803)
  - Liacouras, Peter, 1966-1978 (Box 59, Folder 804)
  - Library of Congress, 1941-1974 (Box 59, Folder 805)
    See also: box 33, folder 438 See also: box 62, folders 842-843
  - Lichtenstein, Julia V., 1959-1974 (Box 59, Folder 806)
  - Light, John J., 1939-1940, 1967-1968 (Box 59, Folder 807)
  - Lindbeck, John M.H., 1961-1970 (Box 59, Folder 808)
  - Lindblom, Charles E., 1955, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 809)
  - Lower Manhattan Cultural Center, 1967-1971 (Box 59, Folder 810)
  - Luce, Henry
  - M, 1928-1949 (Box 59, Folder 811-813)
  - M, 1950-1967 (Box 60, Folder 814-824)
  - M, 1968-1978, undated (Box 61, Folder 825-831)
  - M.I.T. Press, 1964-1973 (Box 61, Folder 832)
    See also: box 52, folder 736
  - McConnell, R.A., 1955, 1963-1975 (Box 61, Folder 833)
  - McCune, Sara Miller
  - McDougal, Myres S., 1940-1974, undated (Box 62, Folder 834-835)
  - McGraw Hill Book Company, 1941-1973 (Box 62, Folder 836)
  - McHale, John, 1963-1977 (Box 62, Folder 837)
  - McKenna, Jeremiah B., 1966-1971, undated (Box 62, Folder 838-840)
  - MacKnight, Jesse M., 1941-1960 (Box 62, Folder 841)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1940-1945 (Box 62, Folder 842-843)
  - McMaster University, 1969-1971 (Box 63, Folder 844)
  - MacMillan Company, 1954-1969 (Box 63, Folder 845)
  - McWhinney, Edward, 1952-1974 (Box 63, Folder 846)
  - Manoni, Mary H., 1968-1973 (Box 63, Folder 847-849)
  - Mansfield, Harvey C.
    See: box 7, folder 85
  - Marcus, George E., 1966-1970 (Box 63, Folder 850)
  - Maritain, Jacques
  - Marjolin, Robert, 1943-1973 (Box 63, Folder 851)
  - Marshall, John, 1940-1958 (Box 64, Folder 852)
  - Marshall (Robert) Civil Liberties Trust, 1955-1958 (Box 64, Folder 853-855)
    See also: box 15, folders 179-188
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Center for International Studies
    See: box 65, folder 865 See: box 77, folders 975-976 See: box 89, folders 1094-1098
  - Mayo, Louis H., 1950-1958, 1966-1973 (Box 64, Folder 856)
  - Mead, Margaret, 1946-1957, 1967-1974 (Box 64, Folder 857)
  - Mead Educational Services, Leadership Conference, 1969
    See: box 65, folders 863-864
  - Meerloo, Joost A.M., 1946-1958 (Box 64, Folder 858)
  - Mendlovitz, Saul
    See: box 23, folders 485-486
  - Merriman, Charles E., 1941-1953 (Box 64, Folder 859-860)
  - Merritt, Richard L., 1964-1974 (Box 65, Folder 861-862)
  - Mershon Center
  - Miller, Richard I., 1969-1971 (Box 65, Folder 863-864)
  - Miller, Thomas Pelham
    See: box 59, folder 810
  - Millikan, Max, 1948-1969 (Box 65, Folder 865)
  - Modley, Rudolf, 1940-1974 (Box 65, Folder 866)
  - Montgomery, John D., 1968-1976 (Box 66, Folder 867)
  - Moore, John, 1968-1973 (Box 66, Folder 868)
  - Morton, Louis, 1969-1970 (Box 66, Folder 869)
  - Mudd, Emily and Stuart, 1973-1974 (Box 66, Folder 870)
  - Myren, Richard A., 1967-1971 (Box 66, Folder 871)
  - N, 1939-1963 (Box 66, Folder 872-877)
  - N, 1964-1976, undated (Box 67, Folder 878-884)
  - Nagel, Stuart S., 1959-1976 (Box 67, Folder 885-886)
  - Namenwirth, Joseph Zvi, 1964-1969 (Box 67, Folder 887-888)
  - Namenwirth, Joseph Zvi, 1970-1975, undated (Box 68, Folder 889-892)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1944, 1958-1978 (Box 68, Folder 893-895)
  - National Book Committee, Inc., 1954-1974 (Box 68, Folder 896-897)
  - National Council on Naturalization and Citizenship, 1946, 1955-1956 (Box 69, Folder 898)
  - National Educational Television and Radio Center, 1959-1974, undated (Box 69, Folder 899-901)
    See also: box 32, folders 422-425
  - National Institute of Social and Behavioral Science, 1959-1977 (Box 69, Folder 902)
  - National Manpower Council
    See: box 29, folders 383-384
  - National Opinion Research Center, 1942-1946 (Box 69, Folder 903)
  - National Research Council
    See: box 29, folders 383-384 See: box 68, folders 893-895
  - National Research Council on Peace Strategy
    See: box 76, folder 962
  - National Science Foundation, 1955-1968 (Box 69, Folder 904-905)
  - National Science Foundation, 1967-1976 (Box 70, Folder 906-908)
  - Neumann, Franz L., 1941-1952 (Box 70, Folder 909)
  - New England Institute for Medical Research, 1959-1967 (Box 70, Folder 910)
  - New School for Social Research, 1942-1971 (Box 70, Folder 911)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1957-1958, 1969-1976 (Box 70, Folder 912)
  - New York County Lawyers Association. Committee on Psychiatry, Psychology and the Law
    See: box 76, folder 965
  - New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Crime, Its Causes, Control and Effect on Society, 1968-1969 (Box 70, Folder 913)
  - New York University, 1940-1972 (Box 71, Folder 914)
  - Nejelski, Leo, 1941-1969 (Box 71, Folder 915-920)
  - Nejelski, Leo, 1970-1974, undated (Box 72, Folder 921-922)
  - Nejelski & Company, Inc., 1950-1952 (Box 72, Folder 923-926)
    See also: box 38, folders 516-526 See also: box 90, folder 1107
  - Newman, Ronald
    See: box 50, folders 698-702
  - Ng, Lorenz Keng-Yong, 1968-1973 (Box 72, Folder 927)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold
  - Nobel Symposia, 1968-1970 (Box 73, Folder 928)
  - Nolte, Richard H., 1947-1973 (Box 73, Folder 929)
  - Northwestern University Press, 1963-1968 (Box 73, Folder 930)
  - O, 1941-1976 (Box 73, Folder 931-935)
  - O'Connor, Dennis M., 1958, 1963-1973, undated (Box 73, Folder 936-937)
  - Ogden (Ralph E.) Foundation
    See also: box 90, folders 1104-1105
  - Ohio State University. Mershon Center, 1964-1978 (Box 74, Folder 938-942)
    See also: box 2, folders 15-16
  - Olom, Louis T., 1940-1975 (Box 74, Folder 943)
  - Oppenheim, Felix, 1951-1972 (Box 74, Folder 944)
  - P, 1937-1970 (Box 75, Folder 945-954)
  - P, 1971-1978, undated (Box 76, Folder 955-956)
  - Padelford, Norman J., 1955-1959, 1966 (Box 76, Folder 957)